Contact

tayana.meridy@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/tayanameridy-bsn-rn-bc-80431b106 (LinkedIn) johnmaxwellgroup.com (Company)

Top Skills

Registered Nurses Leadership Nursing Education

Languages

English

Certifications

John Maxwell Certified Team Member RN-BC

Tayana Meridy, BSN, RN-BC

Registered Nurse, Nurse Consultant, Executive Recruiter, JMT-Coach, Trainer, Mentor, and SAMBCF Director Houston, Texas Area

Summary

I am striving to make a difference in the world starting with myself. I am an experienced Registered Nurse with a demonstrated history of working in the health care industry. As a Nurse Consultant, I partner with organizations to assist moving their valuable assets (employees and business) in an upward direction. My services also include recruiting and HR services. I am a strong entrepreneurial professional who is trying to make a difference by collaborating and assisting organizations to build positive relationships with their employees.

I am a certified John Maxwell Team Member as a trained coach, mentor, trainer, and speaker. I hold Mastermind Groups with likeminded individuals and organizations for personal and professional development. My facilitated groups offer a combination of masterminding, peer brainstorming, education, accountability and support in a group setting to sharpen your business and personal skills. By bringing fresh ideas and a different perspective, my masterminds can help you achieve success. Individual and group coaching services provided.

Nutrition and health are important which leads me to my next adventure of being an independent distributor of Advocare products. I am currently pursing a doctorate degree in Nursing from Capella University.

If you would love to explore what I am passionate about please contact me at 832-907-8897 or message me. I am always interested in speaking with individuals and learning how I can be of value and service to you or an organization. Together we can make the world a better place!

Experience

Non-Profit Organization
Director-Shirley Ann Martin Breast Cancer Foundation
October 2016 - Present (3 years 8 months)

Houston, Texas Area

My mother passed away from breast cancer in 1993. This is a way to honor my mother and all women who has succumb, actively going through treatment, or has become a survivor from breast cancer. It is our hope to educate and provide support to those individuals along with their caregiver and family.

The John Maxwell Team
Professional Mentor, Coach, Speaker and Trainer
September 2016 - Present (3 years 9 months)

Houston, Texas Area

I am passionate about changing the world starting with myself and then spreading it throughout. Offering services to help clients and individuals move forward in their organizations and personally. Offering Masterminds group to Study Leadership, Communications and Growth principles/practices in a group setting, create an action plan and have the group hold you accountable for fulfilling your plan and goals. Offering lunch and learn, executive and personal retreats, individual and group coaching, In-house corporate training, keynote speech for your company sponsored event and the Maxwell Leadership Assessment.

Meridy Staffing Solutions
CEO and Executive Recruiter
September 2015 - Present (4 years 9 months)

Houston, Texas Area

Recruiting and sourcing healthcare professionals from physicians, nursing, and leadership positions. As an independent contractor with General Search and Recruitment, I work with both client companies and job seekers to facilitate placements throughout the US. Active in all aspects of recruiting, interviewing, and placing quality candidates with client companies. Qualify candidates through established recruitment processes that include phone screening, interviewing, making candidate recommendation, reference and background check, networking with clients and candidates. Maintaining business development with potential clients through valuing and building relationship within the business industry.

Meridy Enterprise Inc.

Nurse Consultant-Independent Contractor

June 2013 - Present (7 years)

Page 2 of 5

Houston, Texas Area

Supporting organizations, leadership, staff, and clients by identifying challenges or area of improvements, developing and implementing solutions based on the organizations' needs. Focusing on maximizing productions from employees. Cultivating the organization's culture. Increasing staff, client and customer satisfaction which will result in increase revenue for the organization.

Confidential
14 years 8 months
Utilization Review Nurse
July 2016 - February 2017 (8 months)

Houston, Texas Area

Obtained and document verification of patient eligibility. Worked collaboratively with other entities within the department. Obtained and document verification of patient benefits. Timely managed work lists for cases requiring preauthorization. Worked directly with the payor or assigned third party vendors. Used clinical knowledge and judgment to facilitate with obtaining preauthorization. Provided support to others when clinical input, interpretation, medical necessity justification and peer to peer engagement as needed for patients participating in the clinical trial. Provided assistance with financial counseling to patients which includes reviewing (developing) cost estimates. Completed and timely submit all documents requiring Supervisor or Medical Director approval for financial clearance. Provided support to the Associates as needed and promptly escalate any issues with financial clearance. Completely and accurately documented conversations and communication with Patient Access, payors, third party vendors, patients, and any other representative in and outside of the institution.

Nurse Manager May 2015 - July 2016 (1 year 3 months) Houston, Texas Area

Twenty-Four comprehensive operational responsibilities for the delivery and quality of patient care provided on a medical surgical unit and multi-organ transplant unit. Assisted with developing and implementing performance initiatives to ensuring optimal patient safety and outcomes and customer satisfaction. Demonstrated leadership qualities and critical thinking through self-direction, initiative, effective interpersonal skills and oral/written communications skills. Prepared measurable goals and objectives that are consistent with the organization, and develops action plans for achieving

goals, incorporating collaborative efforts if appropriate. Responded to employee, patient and physician concerns, taking appropriate action and channeling concerns according to appropriate procedures.

Demonstrated the components of the organization's mission and values statements. Planned coverage of unit to maximize the presence of management and staff. Maintained ongoing interactions with patients, families, physicians, and staff on how to improve patient care and service provided. Functioned as role model to staff, reinforcing principles of service orientation and ensuring that the focus is always on improving patient care.

Living Liver Donor Coordinator June 2013 - April 2015 (1 year 11 months)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Coordinated evaluation, admission, discharge, and post-donation care to potential living donors.

Assisted in the evaluation of candidate's suitability for donation, including patient interview, coordinating the medical, surgical, laboratory, radiological, psychological, reviewing evaluation results to verify accuracy. Worked closely with the physician and collaborated with other team members.

Worked closely with the recipient's insurance companies for donor approval. Educated the potential donor, family, and caregiver about the evaluation donation and post donation process.

Reviewed testing to recognize potential problems, abnormal diagnostic finding, and coordinate required care per physician order. Liaison between the patient, physician, ancillary and transplant unit.

Resolved any donor issue if any arises within the scope of practice. Followed UNOS guidelines for evaluation and post donation. Responsible for monthly quality assurance audit. Back up coordinator for the living kidney donor program as needed. Living Kidney Donor Advocate for potential kidney donors. Responsible for monthly audit.

Kidney/Pancreas Coordinator | Staff Nurse | Preceptor | Charge Nurse July 2002 - May 2013 (10 years 11 months)

Columbus, Ohio Area

Coordinated potential solid organ transplant patient workups: screened new referrals for absolute and relative contraindications, served as a liaison with the transplant team, multidisciplinary team, and patient. Worked closely with the insurance companies for preauthorization and authorization for

transplantation. Rotated responsibility for providing on-call coverage for pretransplant patients.

Provided direct care in the clinic setting for potential transplant candidates. Collaborated with transplant surgeons and nephrologists to monitor all perioperative care, i.e. telephone calls, dictated correspondence, laboratory, and diagnostic tests, clinic visits, and referrals. Presented potential transplant recipient case review to Patient Selection Committee and coordinated additional consultations or follow-up diagnostic and laboratory testing per physician order or CTC protocol.

Listed kidney recipients and maintained the waitlist per UNOS and CTC guidelines. Assumed the charge nurse role for a 30-bed unit on the abdominal transplantation unit including the Special Care Unit. The transplant unit was under the critical care area. Supervised nursing staff, non-licensed, and office support personnel. Assisted nurses on the unit during an emergent situation following nursing judgment and protocol. Assigned nursing staff assignments and adjusted nursing staff accordingly. Assigned admitted patients room and nursing staff. Assisted with admissions and other duties to continue the flow of continuity of care. Resolved patient complaints and staff conflict. Assumed preceptor role and responsibilities for nursing students, new graduate registered nurses, and float pool nurses. Chaired the clinical operational committee and quality assurance committee. Created and implemented teaching/learning flow sheets for newly transplanted patients. Facilitated Evidence-Based Practice educational nursing staff in-services to assist in improving the unit's benchmark.

Education

Capella University
Nursing Doctoral Program, Registered Nursing/Registered
Nurse · (2016 - 2021)

Chamberlain College of Nursing
Master's degree, Family Practice Nurse/Nursing · (2016 - 2018)

Western Michigan University
BSN, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (1997 - 2002)